Hey guys, it's me.
I hope you guys are having fun with the course.
Are you ready for more?
Today I'm going to introduce to you a new question type called
short answer questions or questions that require short answers.
There are two goals we need to achieve in today's lesson.
They are understand and identify short answer questions.
Apply five steps for short answer questions effectively.
This lesson has three parts.
Introduction to short answer questions and how to write effective answers.
Steps for short answer questions and practice.
It won't be as difficult as you imagine and I'll guide you through this.
So let's go.
Well, short answer question.
As its name suggests, is a question that requires a short answer.
Let's take a look at the following question.
What name does the writer give to breeds such
as the Persian, Russian Blue and Siamese?
A question of this type has two important parts.
Question words, which is WH words and
content, which is the content of the question.
Question words help us identify the format of the answer.
For example, what is the word form of the answer?
About content, it is obviously necessary
for scanning and finding the correct answer.
And we're going to explore this in part two of the lesson, which is the
steps for short answer questions.
In fact, this question type is not difficult.
You just need to be a little careful when writing the answer.
To make it easier for you, I'm going to give you the rule named WFWC.
W is for words or phrases.
F is for from the passage.
W for within the word limit.
And C come in order.
Firstly, the answers to this question type will only be words or phrases.
For example, they can be nouns or noun phrases, not the whole sentence.
Secondly, the answers to this question type are taken exactly from the passage
without any changes.
Like, don't change the word form.
Don't change the order.
And don't change the singular into the plural and vice versa.
Thirdly, the answers must follow the word limit in the requirement.
Until this lesson, I believe you can understand it well, especially through the
series of lessons on completion questions.
I want to remind you again, when handling this question type, please pay
attention to the requirement and check how many words you are allowed to write.
This is the reason why the answers for this type are only words or phrases,
not the whole sentence.
Please pay attention to this.
Lastly, this is the question type in which the answers come in order.
It means that you will find the answers to question
one before the answer to question two, and so on.
Let's use the WFWC as a checklist.
For this question type, we'll follow five steps.
Step one, read the requirement carefully.
Step two, read questions and identify keywords.
Step three, predict answers.
Step four, apply scanning skills to locate information areas of the questions.
Step five, read the information areas located in
step four carefully to identify correct answers.
Let's take the following passage as an example.
This step helps us to identify the question type and the word limit.
Looking at the requirement quickly, we can recognize
that this is a short answer question with its features.
The requirement is no more than three words, so we can write a maximum of
three words for each answer.
In the exam room, remember to underline this
detail to remind yourself when choosing the answer.
Step two, read questions and identify keywords,
just like other question types of IELTS.
Reading, identifying keywords is a necessary skill.
For this type, the keywords include the WH words or question words.
Now, it's time for the second challenge.
In 10 seconds, you're going to underline the keywords
and identify scanning words, if any, in this question.
Three, two, one, start.
Time's up.
Have you finished?
For this question, we need to focus on the following keywords.
Step three, predict answers.
For this step, we will use the question
words to make predictions about the answer.
This requires us to have a good understanding of English grammar about
different question words.
However, I'll give you a quick summary of them in the following table.
Let's remember this knowledge to identify the correct answers more easily.
For our questions, all of them start with the word what, so we will have
to look for a noun or noun phrase for all of them.
Step four, apply scanning skills to locate information areas of the questions.
Based on the keywords and scanning words we've identified, now you have
30 seconds to locate the information area that contains the answer.
Your time starts now.
From the keyword anxiety in question one, we can
locate the information needed in paragraph one.
In the fourth sentence, we can find the phrase a small amount of anxiety,
which is a synonym of minor anxiety.
Similarly, using the keywords child and acting out, we can easily locate the
information in the second paragraph.
Step five, read the information areas located in step four carefully to
identify correct answers.
We only have one more step.
We need to find a noun slash noun phrase slash proper noun in the passage.
It will be somewhere around the information area we've identified.
As mentioned in the previous step, we could locate
the information needed in the fourth sentence.
A small amount of anxiety is the synonym of minor anxiety.
Be helpful is the same as assist.
And finish a school project means the same as project completion.
The sentence says a small amount of anxiety can provide a boost of energy.
And that is exactly what we need for question one.
For question two, if you look closely in the fifth sentence of the second paragraph,
you can find the exact phrase acting out, which is a keyword we found earlier.
We also found the word misinterpreted, another way of saying perceived.
It's easy to find the answer for question two at the end of that sentence.
Acting out is often misinterpreted as simple disobedience.
In this part, you have three minutes to answer
the three more questions of this passage.
Please pause the video for three minutes and follow all the steps.
Now let's start reading.
If you look closely at the last sentence of the third paragraph, you can find
the phrase value is tied solely to, which
matches our keyword self-worth relies on.
We also see grades or your popularity, which is
another way of saying academic or social success.
It's easy to find the answer for question
three right at the end of that sentence.
The foundation for chronic anxiety is often laid.
Following the word limit, the answer is chronic anxiety.
In the second sentence of the fourth paragraph, you can find the exact word
phenomenon, which is a keyword from our question.
We also found the word inadequate, which
is another way of saying non -fulfillment.
You can find the answer for question four
immediately following the word phenomenon.
It is known as social comparison.
This fits our word limit perfectly.
In the middle of the fifth paragraph, you can find the
word dismissing, which matches our keyword dismissal.
The question asks what adults should avoid, and the text says adults should
listen without doing this.
The answer for question five is found right after that keyword.
Adults should avoid dismissing feelings as just a phase.
That is our three-word answer.
Another lesson, another question type conquered.
We have successfully completed the lesson on short answer questions and
achieved two goals.
Understand and identify short answer questions.
And apply five steps for short answer questions effectively.
Before finishing the lesson, I have two questions to check your knowledge.
Please answer them quickly.
For now, see you all in the next lesson and goodbye.